Now I'm going to talk to you about specific details about the collared shirt that goes underneath your tailored jacket, or your tailored vest, or your tailored coat, etcetera.
You might run in to an issue where the tailor or the designer says, "Would you like a spread collar, or would you like a tab collar?
Would you like your collar to have buttons?
Would you like a regular collar?"
All these different types of collars that you can choose, having never seen them, you might think to yourself, I have no idea what this person is talking about.
So I'm going to go over a couple of line drawings, of four basic collars: the regular normal collar, the spread collar, the button color, and then the tab collar.
So I'm going to take you to the drawings.
Here we have the regular collar, it's very standard.
It has the top button on the, on the, on the top piece and then starts down here.
It's just a regular collar.
Very standard.
Regular.
And then, the spread collar, it's going to be a shorter collar, and there's going to be more space in between here, more space, and it's a little bit shorter.
And then, conversely, is the tab collar.
And the tab collar is going to have extra space up here.
It's probably, I would say in my opinion, you're going to use it when you're more, getting more dressed up.
It's definitely a little bit more formal and it has more of a, of a collar length.
It stands up higher.
And then finally, this is more business attire.
You're going to have button down on the sides, it's just going to have the buttons.
You're going to button down so you can, it's not going to move when you put your tie underneath it, it's going to stay.
So those are the four collars that are pretty standard, pretty typical.
And you can kind of stay within that guideline and make your choices.